http://privacy.umusic.com/se/

This privacy
policy sets out the basis on which any information (which may include personal
data, as defined in data protection law) we collect from you, or that you
provide to us, through this website, application or service (the “Site”) will
be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our
practices regarding your information and how we will treat it.
Please click on
the sections below to learn more about our privacy policy:
·         SOCIAL MEDIA AND OTHER THIRD PARTIES THAT
PROVIDE CONTENT, ADVERTISING OR FUNCTIONALITY ON OUR SERVICES
This site is
operated by Universal Music AB (“We”), Banérgatan 16, 115 23 Stockholm Sweden,
who is a data controller responsible for the processing of personal data under
applicable data protection law. We may share your personal data with UMG
Recordings Services Inc, of 2220 Colorado Avenue, Santa Monica, California,
USA, as an independent data controller under applicable data protection law.
Each of Universal Music AB and UMG Recordings Services Inc. separately make the
disclosures in this Privacy Policy to you (and, where necessary, references in
this Privacy Policy to “UMG” or “we” will be deemed to be references to both
entities for such purpose).
As used in this
Privacy Policy, "UMG Companies" includes all entities UMG controls,
is controlled by or is under common control with, including subsidiaries, joint
ventures or other entities in whom UMG has a substantial ownership interest.
CONTACT
Questions,
comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed by clicking here, or by mail at the relevant address specified
above.
You may contact
UMG’s Data Protection Officer by clicking here.
For questions,
comments or requests not related to this privacy policy please see this FAQ regarding how to contact UMG.
INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU
When you use the
Site or contact us by e-mail, social media, SMS, telephone, or other methods,
we may collect and process the following data about you:
·         Information you give us, including:
o    Forms filled out by you on the Site;
o    Content of correspondence with us by phone,
e-mail or otherwise;
o    Site registration;
o    Subscriptions or orders placed on the Site;
o    Participation in discussion boards or other
social media functions on the Site;
o    Entering a competition, promotion or survey;
o    If applicable, resume, work history, CV, resume
or other job application information;
o    Reporting a problem or requesting support for
the Site.
The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail
address and phone number, date of birth, payment information, personal description,
photographs or images or comments.
·         Information we collect about you.
With regard to each of your visits to our Site we may automatically
collect the following information:
o    Technical information, including IP address,
login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in
types and versions, operating system and platform;
o    Information about your visit, including the
full URL clickstream to, through and from our Site (including date and time);
o    Pages you viewed or searched for; page response
times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction
information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to
browse away from the page.
We may also collect information our about your devices (including
phones, computers or other devices) where you access and visit our Sites. Such
information may include unique device identifiers and mobile network
information (including phone number), IP address, language and time zone,
operating system, hardware version, device locations (including specific
geographic locations, such as through GPS, Bluetooth or WiFi signals).
INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM OTHER
SOURCES
We also work
with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors
in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics
providers, social networks such as Facebook and Twitter, search information
providers, credit reference agencies, third parties who enable sign on functionality
and social network integration) and may receive information about you from
them.
If you choose to
use features on this Site or other UMG websites that connect to your online
profiles, accounts or services (including social media accounts) (“Connected
Accounts”), we may collect any information that you permit through your
settings on those Connected Accounts. For example, if you log in to our site
using your Facebook account and choose to allow Facebook to share your profile
with us, we may collect that information. Information we receive from Connected
Accounts includes email address, first and last name, location (hometown and
country), gender, date of birth, likes, posts or other social activity. Please
review your Connected Account privacy settings to control what information is
provided to us through this option.
If you are
applying for a job at UMG, we may use information you provide to communicate
with third parties regarding your application to the extent permissible by law,
including to verify your credentials, work history, references, conduct
background checks, or other job application-related purposes.
HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED
We may use
information held about you in the following ways:
·         To help us respond to your queries;
·         To provide you with information on
the relevant Universal Music artist;
·         To provide you, or permit selected
third parties to provide you, with information about other goods and services
we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired
about or that we feel may interest you;
·         To make suggestions and
recommendations to you and other users of our Site about goods or services that
may interest you or them;
·         To provide or permit third parties
to provide targeted advertising via websites you visit about goods or services
that you may find interesting (see more on this in our Cookies Policy below;
·         To measure or understand the
effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver
relevant advertising to you;
·         To track the progress and number of
entries in competitions and promotions.
·         To allow you to interact with our
Site, for example by posting comments or to share information from our Site on
third party social media platforms;
·         To carry out our obligations arising
from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the
information, products and services that you request from us;
·         To manage your access to the
services or notify you about changes to the services;
·         To comply with legal and regulatory
requirements;
·         To administer our Site and for
internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing,
research, statistical and survey purposes;
·         To improve our Site to ensure that
content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your
computer;
·         As part of our efforts to keep our
Site safe and secure;
·         If you have applied for a job at
UMG, to review, verify, and evaluate your job application information.
We may combine
information we receive from other sources with information you give to us and
information we collect about you (including information in relation to your
devices). We may use this combined information for the purposes set out above.
For clarity, if
you are a UMG artist, and the Site pertains to royalty payments and your
commercial relationship with UMG, then UMG shall only use your information
collected from such Site to facilitate royalty payments and UMG’s management of
its commercial relationship with you and as otherwise as agreed in your artist
agreement with UMG.
DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION
We may share
your personal data with any UMG Company, listed here, and with selected third parties including:
·         Business partners, suppliers and
sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or
you in order to provide you with a product or service;
·         Business partners, suppliers and
sub-contractors to provide you with information about promotions and offers;
·         Relevant Universal Music artists
and/or their representatives;
·         Advertisers, advertising networks
and social networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts
to you and others. We may also use aggregate and other information to help
advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target. We may make use of
the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our
advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience;
·         Analytics and search engine
providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our Site;
·         Third parties when you consent to or
request such sharing.
We may disclose
your personal data to third parties:
·         In the event that we sell or buy any
business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the
prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
·         If the UMG Company that controls
this Site or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in
which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the
transferred assets;
·         If we are under a duty to disclose
or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in
order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect
the rights, property, or safety of UMG Companies, our customers, or others.
This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for
the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction;
·         To any other third party where
lawful.
STORAGE AND TRANSFER OF DATA
All the
information you provide may be processed and stored, transferred or accessed by
entities around the world as described in this policy. We will take steps to
ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy
Policy. We have put in place technical and organisational procedures designed
to safeguard the information we collected on this Site.
Unfortunately,
the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure.
Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee
the security of your data transmitted to our Site; any transmission is at your
own risk.
COOKIES
Our Site uses
cookies and other tracking technologies to distinguish you from other users of
our Site. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse
our Site and also allows us to improve our Site. For detailed information on
the cookies and other technologies we use and the purposes for which we use
them see our Cookies Policy below.
SOCIAL MEDIA AND OTHER Third Parties That Provide Content, ADVERTISING or Functionality on
Our Services
Some of the content, advertising and functionality on our Site may be
provided by third parties that are not affiliated with us. For example, you may have the opportunity to log in
to our Site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider.
These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to
share certain personal data with us. Services like Facebook Connect give you
the option to post information about your activities on this Site to your
profile page to share with others within your network.
Third-party advertisers also may have a presence on our Sites. These and
other third parties may collect or receive certain information about your use
of our Sites, including through the use of cookies and other Internet
technologies, and this information may be collected over time and combined with
information collected across different websites and online services.
Some of these companies participate in
industry-developed programs designed to provide consumers choices about whether
to receive targeted advertising. Please visit the websites operated by the Network Advertising Initiative, Digital Advertising Alliance, and European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance.
Children
This Site is not directed toward children (as defined by local law) nor
does UMG knowingly collect information from children (as defined by local law)
without parental consent except where in compliance with applicable laws.
YOUR RIGHTS
You may be
entitled, in accordance with applicable law, to object to or request the
restriction of processing of your personal data, and to request access to,
rectification, erasure, and portability of your own personal data by contacting
us as described in the “Contact” section. We may require you to prove your
identity with approved identification if you request this information.
You may also be
entitled, in accordance with applicable law, to lodge a complaint with a
supervisory authority if you consider that our processing of your personal data
infringes applicable law.
You are
responsible for keeping your information current and up-to-date. You may update
your information by contacting us as described in the “Contact” section.
We will retain
your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide
you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply
with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
If you wish to
subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send
the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop
receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe
instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your
account settings page or you can contact us as described in the “Contact”
section.
If you have
applied for a job at UMG, you may have certain rights under your local laws
regarding your application or our evaluation. You may submit any requests to
exercise your rights as described in the “Contact” section.
YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS
California
residents may opt out of having their personally identifiable information
shared with third parties for those third parties' direct marketing purposes by
contacting us as described in the “Contact” section.
Do-Not-Track Signals and Similar Mechanisms. Some web browsers
may transmit “do-not-track” signals to the websites and other online services
with which a user communicates. There is no industry standard that governs
what, if anything, websites should do when they receive these signals. UMG currently
does not take action in response to these signals.
LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES
Our Site, our
newsletters and other communications may, from time to time, contain links to
and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If
you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites
have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or
liability for these policies.
CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY
Any material
changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this
page prior to the change becoming effective and/or we will notify you through
the Site or, where appropriate, by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see
any updates or changes to our privacy policy.
USERS OF SITES IN THE EUROPEAN
ECONOMIC AREA
This section of
this Privacy Policy applies only if you use the Site from a country that is a
Member State of the European Economic Area, and supplements the information in
this Privacy Policy.
Legal Basis
for Data Processing:
We process personal data for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, as
described above. Our legal basis to process personal data includes processing
that is: necessary for the performance of the contract between you and us (for example,
to provide you with the services you request and to identify and authenticate
you so you may use the Site); necessary to comply with legal requirements (for
example, to comply with applicable accounting rules and to make mandatory
disclosures to law enforcement); necessary for our legitimate interests (for
example, to manage our relationship with you and to improve the Site); and
based on consent by our customers (for example, to communicate with you about
our products and services and provide you with marketing information), which
may subsequently be withdrawn at any time (by using preference settings in
emails or on our Sites, using this form, or emailing us as set out in the Contact
section) without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before
its withdrawal.
We may use
automated decision making technologies, including profiling, to support our
data processing activities. Our automated decision making capabilities include
logic that attempts to identify artists, music, communications, products, or
offers that we believe may interest you. By using this logic, it helps us
personalize your interactions with UMG and UMG artists. For you, this means
that you may see online advertisements, direct marketing communications (if you
have subscribed), or other advertising or marketing messages or special offers
based on your activity on our Sites or interactions with UMG Companies or our
third party partners.
In some
instances, you may be required to provide us with personal data for processing
as described above, in order for us to be able to provide you to use all the
features of the Site.
International transfers
Our sharing your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy,
may involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar
degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring, where required by law, at
least one of the following safeguards is implemented:
·         transferring personal data to
countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for
personal data by the European Commission; or
·         using specific contracts approved by
the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in
Europe.
You may
be entitled, in accordance with applicable law, to request a copy of relevant
safeguards by contacting UMG as described in the “Contact” section.
COOKIES POLICY
INFORMATION ABOUT OUR USE OF COOKIES AND
TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES
Our Site uses
cookies and other similar technologies (as described below) to distinguish you
from other users of our Site. This helps us to provide you with a good
experience when you browse our Site, allows us to improve our Site and provide
you with tailored content and advertising.
A cookie is a
small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard
drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is
transferred to your computer's hard drive.
You can find
more information about the types of cookies we use and the purposes for which
we use them in the table below:
Type of Cookie
Purpose
of Cookie
Strictly Necessary
These cookies are essential in order to enable you to browse our Site
and use its features. The information collected by these cookies relate to
the operation of our Site, for example website scripting language and
security tokens to maintain secure areas of our Site.
Performance / Analytics
These
cookies collect anonymous information about how you use our Site, for example
which pages you visit most often, whether you receive any error messages, and
how you arrived at our Site. Information collected by these cookies is used
only to improve your use of our Site and never to identify you. These cookies
are sometimes placed by third-party providers of web traffic analysis
services, such as Google Analytics.
Functionality
These
cookies remember choices you make, for example the country you visit our Site
from, your language and any changes you have made to text size or other parts
of web pages that you can customise, in order to improve your experience of
our Site and to make your visits more tailored and enjoyable. The information
these cookies collect may be anonymised and cannot be used to track your
browsing activity on other websites.
Targeting or Advertising
These
cookies collect information about your browsing habits and inferred interests
in order to make advertising more relevant to you. They are also used to
limit the number of times you see an advert, as well as to measure the
effectiveness of an advertising campaign. These cookies are usually placed by
third-party advertising networks. They remember the other websites that you
visit and this information is shared with third-party organisations, for
example advertisers.
Social Media
These
cookies allow you to share what you’ve been doing on our Site with social
media organisations such as Facebook and Twitter. These cookies are not within
our control. Please refer to the privacy policies of these organisations for
how their cookies work.
Please note that third parties (including, for
example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web
traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are
likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.
We may use cookies:
(i)
to collect anonymised data on users
behaviour on the site. We may also capture what site a user has come from and
what site they go to and also some demographic data (e.g. the user’s location)
and we may use that data to analyse user behaviour across multiple sites;
(ii)
to categorise pools of users (on an
anonymised basis) based on demographic and/or behavioural data and use this to,
(1) target our advertising to cookie-ed users on third party websites and
Universal Music websites, and (2) use that data to allow targeted third party
advertising to categorised cookie-ed users either in respect of advertising
placement UMG has bought/placed and targeted to users on behalf of third
parties or in respect of advertising bought/placed by third parties and
targeted to cookie pools UMG has "sold" to these third parties.
Some of our
Sites may use Google AdSense to publish advertisements, including information
about your demographics and interests. When you view or click on an
advertisement a cookie will be set to help better provide advertisements that
may be of interest to you on this and other websites. You may opt-out of the
use of this cookie by visiting Google’s Advertising and Privacy page: http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html.
Most internet
browsers are automatically set up to accept cookies. However, if you want to
refuse or delete any cookies (or similar technologies), please refer to the
help and support area on your internet browser for instructions on how to block
or delete cookies. Please note you may not be able to take advantage of all the
features of our Site, including certain personalised features, if you delete or
disable cookies.
For more
information on managing cookies, please go to www.allaboutcookies.org, or visit www.youronlinechoices.eu which has further information about
behavioural advertising and online privacy.
Web Beacons
We, or our third party partners, may employ a
software technology called web beacons (also known as web bugs, clear gifs or
pixels) which helps us understand what content is effective, for example by
counting the number of users who have visited these pages, and to understand
usage patterns. Web beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar
in function to cookies, and are used to let us know when content is viewed. In
contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, web
beacons are embedded on web pages, ads, and e-mail. We, or our third party partners,
may tie the information gathered by web beacons to the other information we
collect about you.
In addition to disabling cookies and other
tracking technologies as described above, you may opt-out of receiving targeted
advertising from participating ad networks, audience segment providers, ad
serving vendors, and other service providers by visiting websites operated by
the Network Advertising Initiative, Digital Advertising Alliance, or European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance.
